Guide to the Niger Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Niger collection
1960-1996
MS 1552
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.77
(4 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to political and economic conditions in Niger.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in this collection is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to political and economic conditions in Niger.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Niger -- Economic conditions; Niger -- Politics and government
- Original Accession, 1969, 1986-1993
  - Le Niger: éditions spéciales sur l'onzième anniversaire de la République et sur la bataille pour l'autosuffisance alimentaire, 1969, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Postage stamps: first day covers, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Government documents; journals; reports, 1986-1993, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Dry Season Gardening: A Development Project by an Agency of Interfaith Hunger Appeal (IHA)", 1987 March (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - L'École Nigérienne: organe du Syndicat National des Enseignants du Niger, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Eléments d'Analyse sur L'Ajustement Structurel au Niger," l'Union des Syndicats des Travailleurs du Niger (USTN), [1989?] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Weybi: mensuel d'information de promotion dela femme nigérienne, 1993 March (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Additional Material, 1976-1996; Accession 1998-M-027
  - Alkawali, Pour Un Niger Prospere Dans Une Afrique Unie, 1992 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Amadou, Hama. Discours De Son Excellence Monsieur Le Premier Ministre Hama Amadou (du 25 Février au 13 Mai 1995) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anfani, no. 72, 1995 September 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Convention Democratique et Sociale-Rahama (CDS -RAHAMA)
    - Avant Projet de Reglement Interieur, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Avant Projet de Statuts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fondation SCOA pour la recherche scientifique en Afrique noire. (Projet Boucle du Niger). Histoire du Songhay, 1976 February (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Grande Chancellerie Annuaire des Ordres Nationaux 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ligue Nigerienne de Defense des Droits de l'Homme (LNDH). Les Droits De L'Homme A La Loupe, 1994 February (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National Democratic Institute for International Affairs (NDI). Manuel de l'Observateur: directives applicables a l'observation des elections presidentielles au Niger, 1996 July (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Recueil de Textes Applicables a l'Observation des Elections au Niger, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Republique du Niger. Charte Des Partis Politiques (Acte Fondamental No. XXIV/CN du 03 novembre 1991), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Say, Bania Mahamadou
    - Et La Lutte Continue..., 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Le Cercle des Cocus, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - L'Etonnant Rendez-Vous de L'Histoire, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tiggere Leydi, Wadaande 26 lewru deesambur 1992, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Additional Material, 1963-1987; Accession 2010-M-077
    Arrangement
    The material is arranged as received.
    - Le Temps du Niger: Quotidien Républicain D'Information, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Union: Organe Officiel De L'USTN (Union des Syndicat des Travailleurs du Niger), Circa 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - A.N.P. Information: Bulletin hebdomadaire, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Niger Développement (The Nigerian Embassy France), 1972 Nov, 1973 March-April (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Justice For All flyer, Biafra Students Association in the Americas, 1967 May (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1960-1991; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1960-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)